A Guide to the Ford Foundation records, Mexico City Field Office Program and Subject Files FA1530
Rockefeller Archive Center
Ford Foundation records, Mexico City Field Office Program and Subject Files
1962-1984
Rockefeller Archive Center
Ford Foundation
FA1530
14.61 Cubic Feet 38 boxes (34 letter document containers, 4 legal document containers, and 1 half letter document container)
Conditions Governing Access
Open for research with select materials restricted as noted. Brittle or damaged items are available at the discretion of RAC.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged into 5 series:
1. Mexico Programs, 1962-1982
2. Central America Programs, 1962-1983
3. Caribbean Programs, 1964-1972
4. Latin America Program, 1962-1984
5. International Programs
Each series contains subseries that relate to various Ford Foundation program goals (agriculture, population, etc.). The Ford Foundation's original classifications/titles for series and subseries have been retained.
Biographical / Historical
The Ford Foundation began providing grants to programs in Latin America and the Caribbean in 1959. Within the Latin America and the Caribbean program, the Foundation opened a field office in Mexico in 1962 with three major goals: 1) to help build institutions for research and training, 2) foster leadership and managerial talent by providing grants to institutions and tailored research support to individuals, and 3) study pervasive problems (such as issues in agricultural development). These goals were originally focused in the natural sciences, engineering, economics, community development/management, and agriculture.
By 1967, the Ford Foundation had programs and offices in Argentina, Chile, Peru, Brazil, Colombia, Venezuela, and the Caribbean. In the 1970s, the Ford Foundation widened its program areas in Latin America and the Caribbean to include projects in political science, sociology, social anthropology, women's issues, international affairs, child development, human rights, and demography. In response to the rise of repressive regimes in such countries as Brazil, Chile, Uruguay and Argentina, the Foundation also worked to find employment for displaced social scientists within the region in the 1970s.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
This material was transferred to RAC in 2019 by the Ford Foundation and ingested by RAC as Accessions 2019:012, 2019:015, and 2019:028.
Related Materials
Related materials include:
Ford Foundation records, International Division, Latin America and the Caribbean, Jamaica and Mexico City Field Office Files, 1958-1974 (FA612)
Scope and Contents
This collection primarily consists of correspondence (defined by the Ford Foundation as subject files) received by the Ford Foundation's Mexico City Field Office. The correspondence is related to the Ford Foundation's work in Mexico, Central America, and South America. The topics covered in the correspondence include: agriculture, anthropology, communication, economics, education, work with foundations, human rights, international relations, law and society, Mexico-US relations, nutrition, pollution, population, public management, resources and the environment, rural development, science and technology, social sciences, urban studies, conference files, and trip files.
Correspondence from the following individuals can be found in this collection:
Emily Vargas Adams
Judith D. Albert
Verne S. Atwater
Calvin P. Blair
Frank Cajka
Peter S. Cleaves
Norman Collins
Nancy Dennis
Robert Drysdale
Richard Dye
Peter Fraenkel
Santiago Friedman
John Funari
William K. Gamble
James A. Gardner
Lowell Hardin
Oscar Harkavy
Eugene Havens
Reed Hertford
James Himes
Frank L. Keegan
Robert Myers
John Nagel
John P. Netherton
Siobhan Oppenheimer-Nicolau
K. N. Rao
Nanneke Codd Redclift
Peter Ruof
John Santos
Enid Schoettle
Barry Schuman
Ozzie G. Simmons
Dorothy Tanck
James Trowbridge
Eduardo Venezian
Carl White
Robert S. Wickham
Don Winkelmann
Agriculture -- Research -- Mexico; Community development -- Mexico -- Mexico City; Ford Foundation; Ford Foundation -- Program development -- Education; Ford Foundation programs -- Latin America; Human rights; International relations -- Ford Foundation; Social sciences -- Research -- Population; Women -- Ford Foundation
- Mexico Programs, 1962-1982; 1; 6.55 Cubic Feet
  - Agriculture, 1962-1980; 1
    - General, 1979-1980 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - General, 1970-1978 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Arid Zones, 1967-1969 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Arid Zones, 1962-1966 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - CIMMYT – General, 1970-1972 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - CIMMYT – General, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - CIMMYT/Antonio Narro – Arid Zone, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Chapingo – Campus Planning and Construction, 1963-1965 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Chapingo – General, 1968-1971 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Cornell University – General, 1966-1970 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - IDUR – Instituto de Desarrollo Urbano Y Regional (and University of Southern California), 1973-1975 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - IPADE - Instituto Panamericano de Alta Direccion de Empresas, 1969-1970 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Iowa State University – Chapingo, 1969-1970 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Iowa State University – Chapingo, 1967-1968 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Iowa State representative, 1966-1967
  - Border and Migration in Mexico - US Relations, 1975-1981; 2
    - Border and Migration - (Mexico/US), 1980 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Border and Migration, 1979 June-November (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Border and Migration, 1979 January-May (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - Border and Migration, 1977-1978 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Border and Migration, 1978 July-August (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - Border and Migration, 1978 January-May (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - Border and Migration, 1975-1977 (Box 3, Folder 22)
    - Border and Migration, 1981 (Box 3, Folder 23)
    - Border and Migration, 1980 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Education, 1962-1981; 3
    Scope and Contents
    This subseries contains reports and correspondence regarding Ford Foundation fellows, involvement with Ford-funded programs at universities in Mexico, and Ford-funded educational programming, including Plaza Sésamo (Sesame Street).
    - AAIP - Alumni Association, 1969-1970 (Box 3, Folder 25)
    - American School of Longitudinal Study, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 26)
    - ANUIES (Asociacion Nacional de Ensenanza Superior), 1962-1971 (Box 3, Folder 27)
    - Aptitude Test Mexico - General, 1965-1970 (Box 3, Folder 28)
    - Arizona, University of, 1970 (Box 3, Folder 29)
    - California, University of – Berkeley, 1967-1971 (Box 3, Folder 30)
    - CETYS - Centro de Ensenanza Tecnica Y Superior, Mexicali, B.C., 1967-1972 (Box 3, Folder 31)
    - Plaza Sesamo - CIPAC - INCCAPAC - Advisory Committee Meetings: Guadalajara, Cocoyoc, and Montreal, 1972-1973 (Box 3, Folder 32)
    - CIPAC, 1973 (Box 4, Folder 33)
    - Consejo Nacionol de Fomento Educativo - General, 1976 (Box 4, Folder 34)
    - Centro Mexicano de Escritores - General, 1968-1972 (Box 4, Folder 35)
    - CEMLA - Centro de Estudios Monetarios Latinamericanos, 1966-1969 (Box 4, Folder 36)
    - CEE - Centro de Estudios Educativos - General, 1964-1974 (Box 4, Folder 37)
    - CIES - Centro de Investigaciones Ecologicas Del Sureste, 1978-1979 (Box 4, Folder 38)
    - Childhood Education, 1975-1977 (Box 4, Folder 39)
    - El Colegio de Mexico, 1967-1968 (Box 4, Folder 40)
    - El Colegio de Mexico: Grant Proposal 30th International Congress of Human Sciences, 1976 (Box 4, Folder 41)
      PA76-0831
    - Colegio Peterson, 1969 (Box 4, Folder 42)
    - Comunicacion Educativa, AC, 1975-1977 (Box 4, Folder 43)
    - ETV – General, 1967-1971 (Box 4, Folder 44)
    - ETV – Mexico, 1963-1971 (Box 4, Folder 45)
    - ETV - Monterrey, 1966-1968 (Box 4, Folder 46)
    - Chron Files, 1974 (Box 5, Folder 47)
    - Chron Files, 1973 (Box 5, Folder 48)
    - General, 1975-1977 (Box 5, Folder 49)
    - General, 1973-1974 (Box 5, Folder 50)
    - General, 1972 (Box 5, Folder 51)
    - General, 1970-1971 (Box 5, Folder 52)
    - Education - Mexico, 1977-1980 (Box 5, Folder 53)
    - Escuela Nacional de Bibliotecarios, 1965-1966 (Box 6, Folder 54)
    - Educational Conferences, 1969-1970 (Box 6, Folder 55)
    - Fomento Cultural, A.C. - General, 1973-1974 (Box 6, Folder 56)
    - Fomento Cultural y Educativo, A.C. - Correspondence, 1973-1976 (Box 6, Folder 57)
    - Ibero – Americana, Universidad - Project and Proposal, 1974 (Box 6, Folder 58)
    - Ford Foundation/Intercommunications, 1974-1975 (Box 6, Folder 59)
    - Ford Foundation/Intercommunications, 1970-1973 (Box 6, Folder 60)
    - IMED - Instituto Mexicano del Desarrollo, A.C., 1976-1979 (Box 6, Folder 61)
    - Informacion Educativa, 1975-1977 (Box 6, Folder 62)
    - III - Instituto Interuniversitario de Investigaciones Sociales, Yucatan, 1968-1969 (Box 6, Folder 63-64)
    - INCCAPAC and Chonback Conference, 1975 (Box 7, Folder 65)
    - Instituto Nacional de Pedagogia - General, 1967-1970 (Box 7, Folder 66)
    - CIDOC, 1964-1967 (Box 7, Folder 67)
    - Dr. Pablo Latapi – General, 1968 (Box 7, Folder 68)
    - Leland Stanford Junior University, Regional Grant 700–0401 Monitored by New York Office, undated (Box 7, Folder 69)
      Empty folder except for cross reference sheet - refer to grants PA 07000401 and PA 06900421
    - Linguistics, 1976-1977 (Box 7, Folder 70)
    - Milton Murray - Consultant, 1967-1971 (Box 7, Folder 71)
    - Other University Administration Programs, 1967-1970 (Box 7, Folder 72)
    - Pennsylvania State University, 1967 (Box 7, Folder 73)
      Related to grant PA 06600056
    - Post Graduate Programs, 1968 (Box 7, Folder 74)
    - Punta del Este, undated (Box 7, Folder 75)
      Empty folder with cross reference note - material can be found in the L67-379 log file
    - Scholarly Books in Latin America, 1972 (Box 7, Folder 76)
    - SEP - Secretaria de Educacion Publica, 1975-1976 (Box 7, Folder 77)
    - Sesame Street - General, 1970-1974 (Box 7, Folder 78)
    - Sociedad Matematica Mexicana, 1968 (Box 7, Folder 79)
    - Sociedad Mexicana de Fisica, undated (Box 7, Folder 80)
      Folder empty except for cross reference sheet - See grant no. PA 06800070
    - Stanford University - General, undated (Box 7, Folder 81)
      Empty except for cross reference sheet - see grant no. 06500031 and Log Files L68-108 and L69-421
    - Universidad Autonoma Metropolitina, 1974-1976 (Box 7, Folder 82)
    - Universidad de Guadalajara, 1979-1980 (Box 7, Folder 83)
    - Universidad de las Americas, 1976-1979 (Box 7, Folder 84)
    - UIA - Universidad Iberoamericana, 1974-1976 (Box 7, Folder 85)
    - UIA - Universidad Iberoamericana, 1977 (Box 8, Folder 86)
    - UIA - Universidad Iberoamericana, 1978 (Box 8, Folder 87)
    - UIA - Universidad Iberoamericana, 1978-1981 (Box 8, Folder 88)
    - UNAM – Coordinacion de Ciencias, 1966-1971 (Box 8, Folder 89)
    - UNAM - Facultad de Ingenieria, 1967-1971 (Box 8, Folder 90)
    - UNAM - General, 1964-1972 (Box 8, Folder 91)
    - UNAM - Instituto de Investigaciones Biomedicas, 1968-1970 (Box 8, Folder 92)
    - UNAM – Instituto De Investigaciones Sociales (Lic. R. Benitez Z.), 1971-1972 (Box 8, Folder 93)
    - University Counseling, 1966-1970 (Box 8, Folder 94)
    - UNAM – University Planning, 1966-1970 (Box 8, Folder 95)
    - United Nations, 1967 (Box 8, Folder 96)
    - Washington University, undated (Box 8, Folder 97)
      Empty except for cross reference sheet - refer to Log File L68-456
  - Law and Society, 1976-1978; 4
    - Law and Society - Mexico, 1976-1978 (Box 8, Folder 98)
  - Nutrition, 1979-1982; 5
    - Nutrition - Mexico, 1980-1982 (Box 9, Folder 99)
    - Nutrition - Mexico, 1979-1980 (Box 9, Folder 100)
  - Pollution, 1969-1971; 6
    - Pollution, 1969-1971 (Box 9, Folder 101)
  - Population, 1964-1980; 7
    Biographical / Historical
    The Ford Foundation began population work in Mexico in 1964. Foundation staff moved to provide financial support for training and research in Mexican institutions that would stimulate awareness in both public and private sectors of the facts and meaning of population growth. The Foundation supported research on bio-medical, sociological, and demographic issues related to population, and training of persons who would be capable of contributing to policy and action on population issues.
    The Ford Foundation scaled back its population work in Mexico in the 1970s as the country began accepting population funds from large donors such as the United Nations Fund for Population Activities and the World Bank as well as committing its own resources to population programs. The Foundation continued to fund smaller programs, including the PIACT de Mexico (Program for the Introduction and Adaptation of Contraceptive Technology) and training teachers in population/social communication at the Iberoamerican University in Mexico City.
    - American Embassy, 1973-1975 (Box 9, Folder 102)
    - Arizona State University - "The Future of Mexico" Conference, 1976 (Box 9, Folder 103)
    - Asociacion Mexicana de Facultades y Escuelas de Medicina, 1967-1976 (Box 9, Folder 104)
    - Asociacion Pro-Salud Maternal, A.C., 1969-1974 (Box 9, Folder 105)
    - Center for Population and Family Health/Columbia University, 1976 (Box 9, Folder 106)
    - CICRED – Comité International de coordination des Recherches Nationals en Demographie, 1975-1976 (Box 9, Folder 107)
    - Conferences and Seminars, 1974-1975 (Box 9, Folder 108)
    - Consejo de Planificacion Familiar, 1977-1978 (Box 9, Folder 109)
    - CONAPO – Consejo Nacional de Poblacion, 1975-1980 (Box 9, Folder 110)
    - Culdoscopy Applicants, 1969-1970 (Box 9, Folder 111-113)
    - Culdoscopy Training Program, 1971-1972 (Box 10, Folder 114)
    - Culdoscopy Training Program, 1968-1971 (Box 10, Folder 115)
    - Development Associates, Inc., 1975-1977 (Box 10, Folder 116)
    - Greep Review – Reproductive Biology, 1973-1976 (Box 10, Folder 117)
    - Fellowship File – Carmen Zueck, General Correspondence, 1976-1977 (Box 10, Folder 118)
    - Dr. Reuben Hill (Consultant), 1964-1969 (Box 10, Folder 119)
    - Hospital de la Mujer – Culdoscopy - General Correspondence, 1969 (Box 10, Folder 120)
    - Hospital de la Mujer – Culdoscopy - General Correspondence, 1970 January-August (Box 10, Folder 121)
    - Hospital de la Mujer – Culdoscopy - General Correspondence, 1970 September-December (Box 10, Folder 122)
    - Hospital Infantil, 1964-1969 (Box 10, Folder 123)
    - Instituto Autonomo de Ciencias y Tecnologia (Aguascalientes), 1972-1973 (Box 10, Folder 124)
    - ICOMP - Internal Committee on Population Program Management, 1972-1975 (Box 11, Folder 125)
    - IED - International Educational Development, 1974 (Box 11, Folder 126)
    - IMES – Instituto Mexicano de Estudios Sociales, Proposal – Family Sociology, 1973-1974 (Box 11, Folder 127)
    - Instituto Mexicano del Seguro Social, 1976 (Box 11, Folder 128)
    - IMSS – Family Planning Program, 1972-1974 (Box 11, Folder 129)
    - IPPF - International Planned Parenthood Federation, 1971-1977 (Box 11, Folder 130)
    - Interoffice – Mexico, 1973-1977 (Box 11, Folder 131)
    - Management of Family Planning and Population, 1973-1974 (Box 11, Folder 132)
    - PIACT - Program for the Introduction and Adaption of Contraceptive Technology, 1977-1978 (Box 11, Folder 133)
    - Mexico Program, 1965-1971 (Box 11, Folder 134)
    - Mexico Program, 1972-1973 (Box 12, Folder 135)
    - Mexico Program, 1974-1978 (Box 12, Folder 136)
    - Movimiento Familiar Cristiano, 1973-1974 (Box 12, Folder 137)
    - New York and Field Office - General, 1975-1977 (Box 12, Folder 138)
    - Office of Population - New York City, 1975 (Box 12, Folder 139)
    - Organisacion Regional Interamericana de Trabajadores (ORIT), 1968-1974 (Box 12, Folder 140)
    - PAHO - Pan-American Health Organization, 1966-1977 (Box 12, Folder 141)
    - Non-Parametric Statistics Course – Mexico, 1970 (Box 12, Folder 142)
    - PIACT - Program for the Introduction and Adaption of Contraceptive Technology, 1976 (Box 12, Folder 143)
    - PLAMIRH, 1973-1975 (Box 12, Folder 144)
    - Population - General Correspondence, 1967-1968 (Box 13, Folder 144)
    - Population - General Correspondence, 1969 (Box 13, Folder 145)
    - Population - General Correspondence, 1970 (Box 13, Folder 146)
    - Population - General Correspondence, 1971 (Box 13, Folder 147)
    - Population - General Correspondence, 1972-1973 (Box 13, Folder 148)
    - Population - General Correspondence, 1974-1977 (Box 13, Folder 149)
    - Population - Mexico, 1971-1978 (Box 13, Folder 150)
    - Population Council, 1971-1975 (Box 14, Folder 151)
    - Population Studies, 1973-1974 (Box 14, Folder 152)
    - Population Reference Bureau, 1968-1974 (Box 14, Folder 153)
    - Reproductive Biology, 1968-1976 (Box 14, Folder 154)
    - SSA (Secretaria de Salubridad y Asistencia) - Family Planning Program, 1975-1977 (Box 14, Folder 155)
    - Sanger Center Proposal, 1973-1974 (Box 14, Folder 156)
    - Sex and Population Education, 1973-1977 (Box 14, Folder 157)
    - Social Sciences and Population - General, 1970-1975 (Box 14, Folder 158)
    - UNDA/WACC, 1974 (Box 14, Folder 159)
    - Universidad Autonoma de Guadalajara, 1969-1971 (Box 14, Folder 160)
    - Universidad de Guanajuato - Escuela de Medicina de Leon, 1971 (Box 14, Folder 161)
    - Universidad de Vera Cruz, 1967-1968 (Box 14, Folder 162)
    - Universidad Juarez del Estado de Durango, 1966-1976 (Box 14, Folder 163)
    - University of Chicago - Bogue, 1973-1977 (Box 14, Folder 164)
    - University of Chicago - Communications Training, 1976 (Box 14, Folder 165)
    - University of Notre Dame, 1967-1969 (Box 14, Folder 166)
    - University of Notre Dame, 1966-1971 (Box 14, Folder 167)
    - Visitors - Dr. Bienvenido Delgado Bellini, 1969 (Box 14, Folder 168)
    - Visitors - Eight Nigerian and Ghanian Physicians, 1969 (Box 14, Folder 169)
    - WHO Program of Research, Development and Research Training in Human Reproduction, 1971-1975 (Box 14, Folder 170)
    - World Education, Inc., 1974-1975 (Box 14, Folder 171)
  - Resources and the Environment, 1974-1980; 8
    - Fundacion Javier Barros Sierra, A.C., 1977-1978 (Box 14, Folder 172)
    - Resources and the Environment, 1974-1977 (Box 15, Folder 173)
    - Resources and the Environment, 1978 (Box 15, Folder 174)
    - Resources and the Environment, 1979 (Box 15, Folder 175)
    - Resources and the Environment, 1980 (Box 15, Folder 176)
  - Rural Development, 1972-1979; 9
    - CIDER - Centro de Investigaciones del Desarollo Rural, 1974-1979 (Box 15, Folder 177)
    - COPIDER, 1975-1978 (Box 15, Folder 178)
    - COPIDER - Committee, 1976-1977 (Box 15, Folder 179)
    - COPIDER - Minutes to Reunions, 1975-1976 (Box 15, Folder 180)
    - Rural Development - Mexico, 1978 (Box 16, Folder 181)
    - Rural Development - Mexico, 1974-1977 (Box 16, Folder 182)
    - Universidad Veracruzana, Jalapa, Veracruz, 1972-1979 (Box 16, Folder 183)
  - Science and Technology, 1963-1982; 10
    - Science & Engineering - Harvard University, 1967 (Box 16, Folder 184)
    - ITAM - Instituto Tecnologico Autonomo de Mexico - General, 1963-1969 (Box 16, Folder 185)
    - ITESM - Instituto Tecnologico y de Estudios Superiores de Monterry, 1977-1982 (Box 16, Folder 186)
    - Illinois, University of, 1967-1971 (Box 16, Folder 187)
    - Instituto Politecnico Nacional - General, 1975 (Box 16, Folder 188)
    - Northwestern University, 1967-1969 (Box 16, Folder 189)
    - Nuevo Leon, University of, 1967 (Box 16, Folder 190)
    - Oklahoma, University of, 1968-1971 (Box 16, Folder 191)
    - Oxford Polytechnic, 1969-1971 (Box 16, Folder 192)
    - Pittsburgh, University of, 1967-1970 (Box 16, Folder 193)
    - Santa Clara, University of, 1968 (Box 16, Folder 194)
    - Sociedad Botanica de Mexico, A.C., 1969 (Box 16, Folder 195)
    - Sonora, University of, 1967 (Box 16, Folder 196)
    - Wisconsin, University of, 1968-1969 (Box 16, Folder 197)
  - Social Sciences, 1964-1982; 11
    - CICPAE - Centro de Analises de Informacion y Communicacion en Politica Alimentaria y Politica de Empleo - Estrategias, 1977-1979 (Box 16, Folder 198)
    - IPN - Instituto Politecnico Nacional, 1977-1979 (Box 16, Folder 199)
    - Universidad Anahuac, 1977 (Box 16, Folder 200)
    - Universidad Autonoma Agraria - "Antonio Narro", 1977 (Box 17, Folder 201)
    - Universidad Autonoma Benito Juarez de Oaxaca, 1975 (Box 17, Folder 202)
    - Universidad Autonoma de Guadalajara, 1978 (Box 17, Folder 203)
    - Universidad Autonoma de Nuevo Leon, 1977-1980 (Box 17, Folder 204)
    - Universidad Autonoma de San Luis Potosi, 1977 (Box 17, Folder 205)
    - Texas, University of - Revista Interamericana de Psicologia, 1968-1969 (Box 17, Folder 206)
    - Universidad de Yucatan, 1975-1982 (Box 17, Folder 207)
    - Universidad Autonoma Metropolitana, 1976-1981 (Box 17, Folder 208)
    - Universidad Nacional Autonoma de Mexico, 1975-1981 (Box 17, Folder 209)
    - Social Science - Attachments, 1964-1967 (Box 17, Folder 210)
  - Urban Studies, 1971-1982; 12
    - Urban Studies, 1971 (Box 17, Folder 211)
    - Urban Studies, 1972 (Box 17, Folder 212)
    - Urban Studies, 1973-1982 (Box 17, Folder 213)
- Central America Programs, 1962-1983; 2; 2.28 Cubic Feet 6 letter document boxes
  - General, 1962-1982; 1
    - General, 1976 February-1982 April (Box 17, Folder 214)
    - General, 1966 October-1974 June (Box 17, Folder 215)
    - Belize - General, 1972-1973 (Box 17, Folder 216)
    - Costa Rica – General, 1962-1972 (Box 17, Folder 217)
    - Honduras – General, 1973-1974 (Box 18, Folder 218)
    - Nicaragua – General, 1972-1974 (Box 18, Folder 219)
    - Panama - General, 1976-1982 (Box 18, Folder 220)
  - Agriculture, 1967-1980; 2
    - Agriculture, 1968-1980 (Box 18, Folder 221)
    - AIBDA - Asociacion Interamericana de Bibliotecarios y Documentalistas, 1971 (Box 18, Folder 222)
    - CATIE - Centro Agronómico Tropical de Investigación y Enseñanza, 1974-1979 (Box 18, Folder 223)
    - CSUCA Teacher Training - C.A. Deans of Agriculture - Visit to Mexico, 1967-1968 (Box 18, Folder 224)
    - Costa Rica – Agricultural Benchmark Study, 1967-1971 (Box 18, Folder 225)
    - ICTA - Instituto de Ciencia y Tecnologia Agricolas, 1973-1980 (Box 18, Folder 226)
  - Anthropology, 1977-1980; 3
    - Anthropology, 1977-1980 (Box 19, Folder 227)
  - Education, 1963-1981; 4
    - ETV - El Salvador, 1964-1976 (Box 19, Folder 228)
    - Education - Central America, 1971-1981 (Box 19, Folder 229)
    - FUPAC - Federacion de Universidades Privadas de America Central - Guatemala, 1971-1972 (Box 19, Folder 230)
    - Human Development Project - Guatemala, 1967-1969 (Box 19, Folder 231)
    - Panama - General, 1973 (Box 19, Folder 232)
    - Panama Museum, 1969-1971 (Box 19, Folder 233)
    - Panama, University of, 1968 (Box 19, Folder 234)
    - National Science Foundation, 1963-1964 (Box 19, Folder 235)
    - Nicaragua, National University of, 1967 (Box 19, Folder 236)
    - OTS - Organization for Tropical Studies, 1967-1973 (Box 19, Folder 237)
    - Proyecto Linguistico Francisco Marroquin, Guatemala – General, 1970-1977 (Box 19, Folder 238)
    - Universidad de Costa Rica - General, 1971-1976 (Box 19, Folder 239)
    - Universidad de San Carlos Guatemala - General, 1966-1972 (Box 19, Folder 240)
    - Universidad del Varre, 1966-1976 (Box 20, Folder 241)
  - Human Rights, 1979-1983; 5